Marijn van der Zee

Scrum Master (independent contractor, available)

marijn@serraict.com

Summary

I love to guide software teams on their journey to deliver valuable software and becoming a great team. I enjoy working with the team, but as important is helping the organization to create an environment where teams can shine. I am a Scrum Master, agile developer, pragmatic student, team player and coach and have been active in the field of software development for well over ten years.

You can hire me as an Agile Coach or Scrum Master to serve-slash-lead your Scrum team, take your agile teams to the next level and help your organization adapt to agile software delivery. I am a PSM III certified Scrum Master, love Scrum and am curious to work with any agile software delivery team, Scrum or otherwise.

Experience

Owner at Serra ICT Diensten

November 2009 - Present

Serra helps organizations to grow great software teams that reliably deliver valuable software.

Consultant (independent contractor) at Logiqs Agro

January 2011 - Present

Scrum Master (independent contractor) at Raad van State (Dutch Council of State)

May 2016 - June 2017 (1 year 2 months)

Ensuring that Scrum is understood and enacted by the Scrum Team, within the program KEI and the Raad van State organisation. Helped the program KEI transition to Scrum and continuous delivery. Facilitated team formation within the program; helped the developers self-organize into four teams (2x Scrum, 1x DevOps, 1x waterfall) aligned with the organisation's goals. Started and served two Scrum Teams (not simultaneously) as a Scrum Master. Helped the teams improve their collaboration within the team, between teams, with the organization and the user base. Trained and coached one Product Owner and one fellow Scrum Master.

Scrum Master TransFollow (independent contractor) at TransFollow

January 2015 - March 2016 (1 year 3 months)

Ensuring that Scrum is understood and enacted by the Scrum Team and the TransFollow organisation. Started a Scrum Team and a DevOps team. Served as a Scrum Master to the team, management and the organization. Coached my successor Scrum Master.

When I was no longer needed to serve the team directly, I helped as an Agile Coach by guiding the Scrum Master, Product Owner, two agile teams and the organisation on their journey to deliver the TransFollow platform for exchanging consignment information.

Design Team Lead (ad interim) at Beurtvaartadres BV

April 2014 - January 2015 (10 months)

Coordinating activities for the design team working on the TransFollow project. www.transfollow.com/ - the standardised digital consignment note.

Software Architect, Consultant (independent contractor)

January 2010 - June 2012 (2 years 6 months)

Designing an architecture for a labor registration application to be used in greenhouse horticulture.

Developing software, helping, advising and coaching the development team during construction.

Software Engineer (independent contractor)

March 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 10 months)

Developing some small applications, mainly for the web.

Systems Analist and Software Architect at Logiqs Agro

September 2005 - September 2009 (4 years 1 month)

Technical lead for the application suite Dat-A-Control, a set of applications for controlling various production and logistic processes in automated pot plant nurseries; best compared to MES/WMS systems known from other industries. Project management.

Web Developer at Quel Business Information BV

2001 - 2004 (4 years)

Part-time web developer.

Education

Delft University of Technology

MSc, Mechanical Engineering, specialization Transportation Engineering and Logistics, Mechanical

Engineering, specialization Transportation Engineering and Logistics, 1998 - 2005

Activities and Societies: DSBV Punch (Basketball); Dispuut Transportkunde

Praedinius Gymnasium Groningen

VWO, 1992 - 1998

Nederlandse Basketball Bond

Basketball Trainer 4, 2012 - 2013

Scrum.org

PSM III, PSPO I, PSD I, Scrum, 2015 - 2024

Marijn van der Zee

Scrum Master (independent contractor, available)

marijn@serraict.com



Contact Marijn on LinkedIn